<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Server Management on Reset_Smith's Blog</title><link>https://resetsmith.github.io/posts/server_mgmt/</link><description>Recent content in Server Management on Reset_Smith's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 09:03:55 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://resetsmith.github.io/posts/server_mgmt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Enabling SSL with Apache</title><link>https://resetsmith.github.io/posts/server_mgmt/add_ssl/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 09:03:55 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://resetsmith.github.io/posts/server_mgmt/add_ssl/</guid><description>How we have been installing SSL certificates on our Apache servers Obtain certificate using Certbot Adapted from the Certbot website
Update snapd sudo snap install core; sudo snap refresh core Install Certbot app sudo snap install --classic certbot Prepare the Certbot command sudo ln -s /snap/bin/certbot /usr/bin/certbot If Apache is currently running, disable it so Certbot can use the port sudo systemctl stop apache2.service Test Certbot sudo certbot certonly --dry-run when prompted, select &amp;lsquo;Spin up a temporary webserver&amp;rsquo; when entering the domain name, you can list multiple targets ie: casat.</description></item><item><title>Setting up password authentication with Apache</title><link>https://resetsmith.github.io/posts/server_mgmt/htpasswd/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 10:03:55 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://resetsmith.github.io/posts/server_mgmt/htpasswd/</guid><description>This is referred to as Apache &amp;lsquo;Basic Auth&amp;rsquo;. Following these directions will add a username and password prompt to a website or specific webpage. Typically we use this to hide a &amp;lsquo;Dev&amp;rsquo; website so it can still be accessible but not open to the public.
Using htpasswd to generate users and passwords Install Dependencies Make sure you have Apache Extended Utilities installed sudo apt update sudo apt install apache2-utils Create first user with htpasswd sudo htpasswd -c /etc/apache2/htpasswd.</description></item></channel></rss>